Guide to the Cal Dean Hill, Jr. and Virginia Lee Smith papers, 1941-1978 MS 890
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Cal Dean Hill, Jr. and Virginia Lee Smith papers
1941-1978
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hill, Cal Dean, Jr.; Smith, Virginia Lee
MS 890
2 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
39.1 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS890aip_001 (39.1 GB)
This collection mainly contains Cal Dean Hill, Jr., Virginia Lee Smith, and their son Howard Hill documenting their time at Rice University.
Content Description
This collection mainly contains class notes and other related materials from Cal Dean Hill, Jr., Virginia Lee Smith, and their son Howard Hill. There are also two scrapbooks documenting the early life of Cal Dean Hill, Jr.
Biographical / Historical
Cal Dean Hill, Jr. (1930-2017) and Virginia Lee Smith attended Rice Institute from the late 1940s to the early 1950s. Their son Howard attended in the 1970s.
After graduation and a two year stint in the Navy, Cal Dean Hill, Jr. became an architect. His son, Howard, also went on to become an architect after earning his degree from Rice.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials purchased at an estate sale by Melissa Kean.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Rice University -- History; Social life and customs
- Series I: Academics
  - Architecture 455, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biology 100, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - English 307, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - English courses, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - French courses, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - HART 345, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - HART 346, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History courses, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Math 100, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 220, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Physics 100 laboratory manual, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series II: General files
  - Ephmera, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - News clips, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Rice song book, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series III: Scrapbooks
  - Cal Dean Hill, Jr. scrapbook, 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Cal Dean Hill, Jr. scrapbook, 1942-1948 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Lee Smith scrapbook, 1925-1949 (Box 3)
  - Virginia Lee Smith and Cal Dean Hill, Jr. scrapbook, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
- Series IV: Digital files
  - Rice-related images, 1949-1953
    Scope and Contents
    Contents include: Master tiff and access jpgs contain images related to the lives of Cal Dean Hill, Jr. and Virginia Lee Smith
  - Rice-related images, 1976-1982
    Contents include: Master tiff and access jpgs contain images related to the life of Howard Hill.
  - Rice-related images, 2010
    Contents include: Master tiff and access jpgs contain images related to the life of Nicholas Hill.